Abner Dean papers ML-44
Rauner Special Collections Library
- Papers, 1926-1981; 1
  - Illustrations - Magazines, 1933-1976 (Box 4)
    Illustrations - Magazines
    - Misc. illustrations from medical journals, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Misc. material from "Life" magazine, undated3 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "New York Times" and New "York Times Magazine", 1941-1949 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "New York Times" and New "York Times Magazine", 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "New York Times" and New "York Times Magazine", 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "New York Times" and New "York Times Magazine", 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Newspapers: "The American Weekly", 1955-1959 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Newspapers: "Journal-American Pictorial Review", 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Newspapers: "Journal-American Saturday Home Magazine"; April 16, 1938 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Newspapers: "New York Herald Tribune", 1957-1958 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Newspapers: "Today's Living," December 23, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Original drawings used in "The Strange World of 1984," author unidentified; in "Life," July 16, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Pamphlets: All About Wool, by the Wool Bureau, Inc., undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Pamphlets: Travel Tips, by Abner Dean; published by Bloomingdale Bros.; New York, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Pamphlets: What It Takes To Be A "Pro," by A. F. Frazier, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Sketches to illustrate an article by Lowell Thomas, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Theatre: Announcements for George Bernard Shaw's "Too True To Be Good", undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Theatre: Announcements for "Never Live Over A Pretzel Factory", undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Theatre: Magazine: Playbill; March 11, April 8, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Theatre: Newspaper ads for "Pinny and the Witches", 1959 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Theatre: Newspaper ads for "Pinny and the Witches"; finished drawings, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Theatre: Newspaper ads for "The Heavenly Twins", 1955 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Theatre: Newspaper ads for "Never Live Over A Pretzel Factory", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Theatre: Newspaper ads for "Too True To Be Good", 1963 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Theatre: Poster: "Never Live Over A Pretzel Factory", undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Theatre: Poster: "Too True To Be Good", undated (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Theatre: Program: "Too True To Be Good", published by the Program Publishing Co, New York, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Theatre: Program covers for "Guys and Dolls", undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Watercolors; misc., undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Index cards, labelled', ideas for further resolution and selection, undated (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - List of Abner Dean drawings at the Hood Museum at Dartmouth College, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Lists of Dean's accomplishments, i.e., books, exhibits, magazine illustrations, TV appearances, lecture engagements, etc., undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Magazine Clippings, 1934-1968 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Magazine Covers: "American Journal of Nursing", 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Magazine Covers: "American Journal of Nursing"; color rush and magazine, March, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Magazine Covers: "American Legion Magazine"; August, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Magazine Covers: "College Humor", undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Magazine Covers: "Common Sense"; March 16, 30, April 13, 27, May 11, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Magazine Covers: "Crossword Varieties", 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Magazine Covers: "Dartmouth Alumni Magazine", 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Magazine Covers: "Life"; with photo of Roosevelt mask used in the illustration, and proof of cover, September, 1932 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Magazine Covers: "Modern Youth"; April, May-June, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Magazine Covers: "The New Yorker", 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Magazine Covers: "The Pictorial"; Commencement Issue, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Magazine Covers: "Psychology Today"; September, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Magazine Covers: "The Sun Dial", Family Magazine of the Sun Oil Co., 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Magazine Covers: "Superb Crossword Puzzles", 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Magazine Covers: "Sybil Leek's Astrology", 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Magazine Covers: "Sybil Leek's Astrology Journal"; January-December, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Magazine Covers: "This Week Magazine"; July 4, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - Magazine Covers: "Universal Crossword Puzzles"; August, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - Magazine Covers: "The Bungei-Shunju"; March, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Magazine Covers: "The Cartoonist"; Fall, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Magazine Covers: "Dance Magazine"; April, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Magazine Covers: "Dartmouth Alumni Magazine"; May, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Magazine Covers: "'47, the Magazine of the Year"; October, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Magazine Covers: "Greensleeves", undated (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Magazine Covers: "Jack-O-Lantern", 1928 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Magazine Covers: "Life"; October, December, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Magazine Covers: "Life", 1942-1947 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Magazine Covers: "Life", 1948-1954 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Magazine Covers: "Modern Youth"; February-June, 1933 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Advertisements - Book Mss: " Wake Me When It's Over", 1935-1960 (Box 1)
    Advertisements - Book Mss: " Wake Me When It's Over"
    - Advertisements: Aetna Insurance Group: Layouts, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Advertisements: Aetna Insurance Group: Layouts, 1945-1949 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Advertisements: Insurance Group: Layouts, 1950-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Advertisements: Aetna Insurance Group: Layouts, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Advertisements: Aetna Insurance Group: Magazine: "The Messenger," Autumn, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Advertisements: Article: The "Flying Carpet" of Today Means Controlled Safety and Smooth Riding, by Siler Freeman; in an ad for the National Safety Council, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Advertisements: The Blue Network, Blue Network Company, a Radio Corp. of America service, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Advertisements: Burlington Mills, in "Women's Wear," July 27, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Advertisements: Femme and Moustache colognes; glossies, paste-ups and proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Advertisements: Gripper Fasteners, Scovill Manufacturing Co.; in "Life," May 31, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Advertisements: Huyler's Stores, Chicago, Illinois, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Advertisements: John Jameson Whiskey, W. A. Taylor and Co., New York, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Advertisements: Kellogg's Wheat Pops, Kellogg's Co., 1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Advertisements: Kolantyl, Merrill-National Ltd., London, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Advertisements: Movie ads, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Advertisements: Old Gold cigarettes, Lorillard Co.; illustrations, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Advertisements: Old Gold cigarettes, Lorillard Co.; newspaper proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Advertisements: Old Smuggler Whiskey, W. A. Taylor and Co., New York, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Advertisements: Owen-Fields, Inc., undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Advertisements: Pfizer college placement ad; Charles Pfizer and Co., Inc., New York, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Advertisements: R. H. Macy and Co., New York, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Advertisements: School Art League, New York, 1935-1937 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Advertisements: Seagram Distillers Corporation, New York, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Advertisements: Ship 'n' Shore Sportswear, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Advertisements: Sonotone Hearing Aids, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Advertisements: "Time" Magazine in the "New York Times," November 18, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Advertisements: Underwood-Elliott-Fisher Co., typewriters, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Advertisements: Upjohn Co., Orinase series, 1958-1960 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Biography, for use in America's Young Men, Vol. Ill; printer's proof, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Book jackets: "Abner Dean's Naked People," by Abner Dean; final design, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Book jackets: "And On The Eighth Day," by Abner Dean; original drawings, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Book jackets: "And On The Eighth Day," by Abner Dean; proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Book jackets: "The Book of the It," by Georg Groddeck; watercolor sketches and proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Book jackets: "Cave Drawings For the Future," by Abner Dean; final design, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Book jackets: "Cave Drawings For the Future," by Abner Dean; original drawings, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Book jackets: "Cave Drawings For the Future," by Abner Dean; proofs, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Book jackets: "Come As You Are," by Abner Dean; end papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Book jackets: "Come As You Are," by Abner Dean; final design, undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Book jackets: "Come As You Are," by Abner Dean; proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Book jackets: "Eros and Civilization," by Herbert Marcuse; proofs, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Book jackets: "It's A Long Way To Heaven," by Abner Dean; final design, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Book jackets: "It's A Long Way To Heaven," by Abner Dean; proofs, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Book jackets: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Book jackets: "Not Far From The Jungle," by Abner Dean; cover design, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Book jackets: "Not Far From The Jungle," by Abner Dean; end papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Book jackets: "Not Far From The Jungle," by Abner Dean; final design, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Book jackets: "Not Far From The Jungle, by Abner Dean; original drawings, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Book jackets: "Wake Me When It's Over, by Abner Dean; end papers, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Book jackets: "What Am I Doing Here?" by Abner Dean; original drawing and proof, undated (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Book Mss: "And On the Eighth Day"; pages from the book, pasted up, incomplete, undated (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Book Mss: "Cave Drawings For The Future"; pages from the book, incomplete, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Book Mss: "Come As You Are"; pages from the book, incomplete, undated (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Book Mss: "It's A Long Way To Heaven"; pages from the book, undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Book Mss: "Not Far From The Jungle"; first eight (8) drawings, undated (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Book Mss: "Not Far From The Jungle"; pages from the book, incomplete, undated (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Book Mss: "Not Far From The Jungle"; verses, carbon copy, undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Book Mss: "Wake Me When It's Over"; compositor's dummy, undated (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Book Mss: "Wake Me When It's Over"; illustration pages, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Advertisement: Posters for BC pain reliever; Book MSS: "Not Far From The Jungle," artwork for al..., 1955-1971 (Box 6)
    Advertisement: Posters for BC pain reliever; Book MSS: "Not Far From The Jungle," artwork for all artwork and some drawings; "Wake Me When It's Over," camera ready illustrations; Building system: Cross sections of beams, interlocking pieces, floor plans (1971); Cartoons for "American Journal of Nursing," "Cosmopolitan," "Rockefeller Center Weekly," " Redbook," "Newsweek"
  - Cartoons for "Come As You Are," "Collier's Magazine," "Medical World News," "American Journal of..., 1950-1965 (Box 7)
    Cartoons for "Come As You Are," "Collier's Magazine," "Medical World News," "American Journal of Nursing," "Swimming Pool-Bruce Learned - Connecticut," "Elks Magazine" and New York Herald Tribune"; Illustrations: Drawings used in "Life" Magazine articles (1950)
  - Illustrations: Book: "Not Far From The Jungle," preliminary, rough drawings on cardboard; Painti..., undated (Box 8)
    Illustrations: Book: "Not Far From The Jungle," preliminary, rough drawings on cardboard; Painting: Still life in oils
  - Paintings: "Wash Day, Scacave Zagorje" by Roharka, watercolor; Watercolor fantasies; Photograph ..., 1973 (Box 9)
    Paintings: "Wash Day, Scacave Zagorje" by Roharka, watercolor; Watercolor fantasies; Photograph Album: Building systems, folding table, sculptures
  - Prints: Black and white prints of the works of Honore Daumier; "Cezanne, 10 Watercolors"(1947); ..., 1926-1953 (Box 10)
    Prints: Black and white prints of the works of Honore Daumier; "Cezanne, 10 Watercolors"(1947); Chinese lesson aids; Men floating with the aid of a balloon; Man with a basket of stars; Two bugs conversing; Two man fighting each other; "Paradise Lost" by William Blake, watercolors; Sketchbook: Pen and ink drawings (1952-1953); Sketches: Cats and other animals, early black and whit portraits (1926-1932)
  - Sketches: Ethel Dean, horses' skull (1947), drawing for Dean's sculptures (1938-1954), pen and i..., 1938-1955 (Box 11)
    Sketches: Ethel Dean, horses' skull (1947), drawing for Dean's sculptures (1938-1954), pen and ink drawing of solitary figures (1951), drawings of fish standing on their tails, studies of female nude, study of woman's head (1955)
  - Cartoons by Ethel Dean: Black and white for "New York Times" and "New York Herald Tribune," fini..., 1941-1955 (Box 12)
    Cartoons by Ethel Dean: Black and white for "New York Times" and "New York Herald Tribune," finished drawing "One Damn Foot After Another," sketches illustrating scenes from "Green Mansions" by W. H. Hudson
  - Sketches by Ethel Dean: Illustration for "The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam," drawings used in articl..., 1941-1955 (Box 13)
    Sketches by Ethel Dean: Illustration for "The Rubaiyat of Omar Khayyam," drawings used in article "The Strange World of 1984" (1949), multilevel folding table, insects, birds and animals from earlier sketchbooks (1954-1955); Paintings: Watercolor landscapes (1941)
  - Ethel Dean: Wallpaper design; Illustration: Drawings from the book, "Cave Drawings For The Futur..., 1954 (Box 14)
    Ethel Dean: Wallpaper design; Illustration: Drawings from the book, "Cave Drawings For The Future"
  - Illustrations: Drawings from the book,"It's A Long Way to Heaven" I, 1949 (Box 15)
    Illustrations: Drawings from the book,"It's A Long Way to Heaven" I
  - Illustrations: Drawings from the book,"It's A Long Way to Heaven" II, 1949 (Box 16)
    Illustrations: Drawings from the book,"It's A Long Way to Heaven" II
  - Building System: Measurements of building model and types of material used in the model, undated (Box 17)
    Building System: Measurements of building model and types of material used in the model
  - Building system: Plans for assembly of building model, 1970 (Box 18)
    Building system: Plans for assembly of building model
  - Cartoons: Drawings entitled "How Much of Me Is Me?" from the book "What Am I Doing Here?", 1947 (Box 19)
    Cartoons: Drawings entitled "How Much of Me Is Me?" from the book "What Am I Doing Here?"
  - Cartoons: Drawings and cut-out pieces for an animated cartoon sequence, undated (Box 20)
    Cartoons: Drawings and cut-out pieces for an animated cartoon sequence
  - Ethel Dean: Painting: "Bridge", undated (Box 21)
    Ethel Dean: Painting: "Bridge"
  - Ethel Dean: Painting: "Horizon", undated (Box 22)
    Ethel Dean: Painting: "Horizon"
  - Illustration: Drawing used in John Dos Passos' article, "The Failure of Marxism" in "Life", undated (Box 23)
    Illustration: Drawing used in John Dos Passos' article, "The Failure of Marxism" in "Life"
  - Illustrations: Drawings from the book "An On The Eighth Day" finished sketches, undated (Box 24)
    Illustrations: Drawings from the book "An On The Eighth Day" finished sketches
  - Illustrations: Original drawings used in the article, "The Strange World of 1984," author uniden..., 1949 (Box 25)
    Illustrations: Original drawings used in the article, "The Strange World of 1984," author unidentified, in "Life" July 16, 1949
  - Multilevel folding table: Assembly plans, undated (Box 26)
    Multilevel folding table: Assembly plans
  - Painting:Self-portrait of Abner Dean in oils, undated (Box 27)
    Painting:Self-portrait of Abner Dean in oils
  - Sketches: "Broadway 1932", undated (Box 28)
    Sketches: "Broadway 1932"
  - Sketches: Miscellaneous sketches in various mediums and styles, 1938-1953 (Box 29)
    Sketches: Miscellaneous sketches in various mediums and styles
  - Sketches: Rough and finished drawings entitled "The Neighbor," done for CBS TV's program "Lamp U..., 1955 (Box 30)
    Sketches: Rough and finished drawings entitled "The Neighbor," done for CBS TV's program "Lamp Unto My Feet," April 17, 1955
- Addendum 1, 1949-1969; 2
  Cartoons, sketches, drawings and illustrations for a variety of books and magazine articles.
  - Box: 31, 1949-1969 (Box 31)
    Box: 31
    - Cartoons: Group of people performing party tricks, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Cartoons: Party scene of people standing in water; published in Show Magazine, March, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Glass negatives; drawings used in The Strange World of 1984, in Life, July, 16, 1949 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Clearer View on Protection for Partners In Practice," author unidentified in "Medical World News," June 18, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Doctor's Good Will Gets Better Tax Treatment," author unidentified; in "Medical World News," October 8, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "MD's Tax Audit Need Not Be a Bitter Pill," author unidentified; in "Medical World News," August 20, 1965 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "New Light on Living Matter," by Albert Szent-Gyorgyi; source unidentified, undated (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Peter Principle," by Lawrence J. Peter and Raymond Hull; in "Medical Economics," November 10, 1969 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Road to Genetic Progress," by Hermann J. Muller; in "Medical World News," February 28, 1964 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Prints: One foot entering the outlined space as another foot leaves it; rough sketch included, undated (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Sketches: Drawings used for Christmas cards, undated (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Sketches:Grasshoppers, crickets, bees, etc, as corresponding to instruments in an insect "orchestra", undated (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Sketches:Original drawings for sculptures, 1952 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Sketches: Original drawings for sculptures, 1953 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Box: 32, 1949-1952 (Box 32)
    Box: 32
    - Caricature: A woman wearing a black dress with a white lace collar; oval watercolor, undated (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Cartoon: Man rising from an egg carton; rough and finished drawings, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Glass negative: Drawing used in "The Strange World of 1984," in "Life," July 16, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Prints: Flora With Fauna, by Abner Dean; published by F.A.R. Gallery, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Sketches: Original drawings for sculptures, 1949 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Sketches: Original drawings for sculptures, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Box: 33, undated (Box 33)
    Box: 33
    - Drawings from the book, "What Am I Doing Here?", undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - Drawing: "The Queens Husband", undated (Box 33, Folder 2)